romanoriginals.co.uk 2019-04-22

# Privacy Policy | Roman Originals

Privacy Policy 

Here at Roman, we are committed to respecting the privacy and security of all users and visitors to romanoriginals.co.uk. This policy sets out the basis for which information collected about you by Roman. 

By submitting your information and using our Website, you consent to the collection, storage and processing of your personal information by us in the manner set out in this privacy policy. 

This policy sets out how information about you is collected and used by Roman strictly in accordance with all current data protection laws, including the EU2016/679 General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) (Amendment) Regulations 2011. 

For the purpose of the EU2016/679 General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the data controller is Roman, 5 Wingfoot Way, Birmingham, B24 9JH. For any privacy queries please contact dataprotection@romanoriginals.co.uk

The personal data you share with us will only be used for the specified purposes documented below and will never be shared with any third party. 

Where we use the terms “we” “us” “our” “Roman” and “Roman Originals” we are specifically referring to Roman Originals PLC. 

From time to time this Privacy and Cookie Policy may change. We recommend that you check this page each time your visit or submit personal information to Roman. 

When you use the romanoriginals.co.uk website (Browsing or purchasing), engage with Roman on Social Media, participate in Competitions, contact our customer care teams, or visit one of our stores, we may collect and process the following personal information about you: 

\- Information that you submit at time of registering to use our site, using guest checkout, shopping online or in store, subscribing to any marketing material, contacting our customer care team or entering a competition. 

\- Information collected may include name, billing and delivery addresses, credit, debit card details email address and phone number. This information will be used to help to answer your queries, to process your order or to allow you to participate in competitions or to send your marketing material which we think is relevant or interesting to you 

\- Details of your visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data. We will also use your Internet Protocol (IP address) to collect traffic data. We will not use your IP address to identify you personally. This information may be used to present the website in the most effective manner for your browser or to administer the website and improve our services to you. 

\- If you use sign into our site, using Facebook or Google, you are granting permission to these third party sites to share user details such as name, email address, gender, date of birth or location to enable you to sign in to Roman. 

\- Engaging with Roman content including “likes”, “retweets”, “reposts”, “shares”, may allow us to interact with you or access your accounts on social media. It may also involve you submitting a photo or video of you. We would encourage you to check the terms and conditions of the social media providers. 

The nature of how we process your personal information will differ depending on purpose. If you have subscribed to Marketing updates, your personal data can be withdrawn at any stage. Where you have shopped online, your data will be used to process your order. We will only pass on your personal information to third parties to facilitate delivery of your order (e.g. name and address and telephone number to distribution carriers). We share personal information with three separate third parties in order to complete your transaction: 

Our ecommerce Platform Provider. We pass along information so that they may process card transactions, screen for fraud, and conduct other activities integral to running a website. In addressing fraud prevention, we may disclose your address details to them to check against various Fraud Prevention Schemes 

Our Carriers. We pass along your information to our carriers so that they may deliver your order to you. 

Transaction Partners: We have a relationship with PayPal, and will send information to them for payment processing if you select that option during Checkout. 

We will never collect sensitive personal data such as race ethnic origin, physical or mental health, political or philosophical views or sexual orientation. 

We do not knowingly collect information from Children under the age of 13 either online or in our stores. Children under the age of 13 are not permitted to use or submit information on romanoriginals.co.uk 

We take all steps necessary to ensure that information we collect is kept secure, confidential and stored on servers, hidden behind firewalls and always password protected. 

We use the latest in Secure Server Technology (SSL) to protect your data to the highest standards. 

Data that we collect from you may be stored at a destination outside the European Economic Area. Please be assured that it will only processed by staff operating for Roman or one of our trusted suppliers for processing your payment details or fulfilling your order. By submitting your data online or in one of our stores, you are agreeing to this transfer, storing or processing of your personal details. 

You have the option to save your credit or debit card details once your order has been processed to make future orders easier. However you will need to enter your card’s 3 digit security code for every transaction for security purposes. It is your responsibility to keep all passwords associated with Roman confidential and secure. We will never email or telephone you to ask for your security information or log on details. 

You have the right to your personal data help by Roman. This means you have the right to: 

  * Access the personal information we hold about you at any time.
  * Request that Roman change or update out of date personal information which we hold about you.
  * Have personal data we hold about you, deleted from all of our systems
  * Receive a copy for personal data which we hold about you transmitted to another party
  * Restrict the processing of any or all of your personal data

Please email dataprotection@romanoriginals.co.uk for more details. If you do request any of the above, Roman reserves the right to verify your identity and request that you provide proof of identity. 

You may wish to stop interacting or engaging with Roman across any or all of our social media platforms. Please let us know if at all you wish to stop engaging by emailing dataprotection@romanoriginals.co.uk

The Roman websites or social media site may from time to time contain links to and from partner, advertising and affiliate websites. If you do follow a link to these websites please note that these websites will have their own privacy and cookie policy and Roman cannot accept any responsibility for these policies. 

If you have subscribed to receive Marketing from Roman, we will use your details to send you updates on Roman products and services which we deem most relevant to you. You have the right to ask us not to process your personal details for such purposes and you can change your mind and ‘opt out’ of receiving marketing updates at any time. 

Simply ‘unsubscribe’ at the bottom of any email which you receive. 

If you have an account with us, select Sign In / log-on, and change your preferences 

Send an email to, writing “unsubscribe” in the subject heading to customerservice@romanoriginals.co.uk

Cookies are files stored on your computer when you visit certain web pages. Romanoriginals.co.uk uses cookies to keep track of what you have in your basket, and to remember you when you return to our site. 

To place an order on romanoriginals.co.uk, you need to have cookies enabled. If you don't wish to enable cookies, you'll still be able to browse the site and use it for research products. Most web browsers have cookies enabled, but have a look at the Managing Cookies section for help to turn them on should you need to. 

Cookies can't harm your computer. 

We don't store personally identifiable information such as credit card details in cookies we create. We use information gathered from cookies to make romanoriginals.co.uk better for you, for example, they help us to identify problems, fix errors and to improve our page designs. 

We also use the information from cookies to identify related products and products you may like based on what you have looked at whilst using romanoriginals.co.uk. We also work with carefully chosen and monitored suppliers who may set cookies during your visit to romanoriginals.co.uk. 

These cookies are used for re-marketing - this means they are used to show you advertisements for different products and services based on what you appear to be interested in. You can easily opt out of these cookies by going to the Network Advertising Initiative website. This link will open in a new window - we're not responsible for the content of external websites. 

In addition to re-marketing, a lookalike audience may also be built to identify customers who may have similar interests to you. This audience is identified through using a custom audience which includes either a customer’s email address or phone number. The custom audience is shared in an encrypted format to maintain privacy. Roman remains responsible for managing this data and the audience selection. The uploaded encrypted data is compared against a partners encrypted data to identify a lookalike audience. Customers identified through a lookalike audience can then be targeted with relevant online advertising. Please note, this lookalike audience is only used by Roman and the data processor aligns with GDPR. Customers can request to be removed from this targeting by contacting dataprotection@romanoriginals.co.uk

We're sharing this information with you to comply with recent European legislation, but more importantly to ensure that we’re honest, clear and upfront about your privacy when using our website. 

To make full use of the online shopping and personalised features on romanoriginals.co.uk, your computer, tablet or mobile phone will need to accept cookies. This is because the shopping basket needs to use cookies to function and because we can only provide you with certain personalised features of this website by using them. 

Our cookies don't store sensitive information such as your name, address or payment details. They do hold a “key” that allows us to associate information with your computer when you are shopping with us or when you come back to visit us. 

We split the cookies that we use into 4 different types: 

**1\. Strictly Necessary Cookies**  
These cookies are essential for you to use the shopping features of romanoriginals.co.uk; they enable you to add items to your shopping basket, to checkout and to use the My Account section of the site. These cookies are not used to advertise products or services to you. 

**2\. Performance Cookies**  
These cookies collect information about how you use romanoriginals.co.uk, for instance the pages you visit most often or any error messages you may see on the pages you visit. These cookies don’t collect your personal information. The information we collect is used to improve how our website works. 

These cookies are **not** used to advertise products or services to you. 

**3\. Functional Cookies**  
These cookies allow the romanoriginals.co.uk website to remember items such as your user name, the region you are shopping in and more personal features like product recommendations. The information these cookies collect is anonymous and cannot be used to track your activity on other websites. 

These cookies are **not** used to advertise products or services to you. 

**4\. Targeting Cookies**  
These cookies are used to advertise products and services to you. 

These cookies are used to make our advertising more relevant to you and your interests. We also use them to limit the number of times you see an advertisement and to measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. 

These cookies may be placed on your computer, tablet or mobile phone by us or by a third party with our consent. 

When these cookies are placed by us, they may be used only by us. When these cookies are placed by a third party with our consent, they may be used by that third party and other parties to make adverts more relevant to you and your interests. Examples of this include various social networks such as Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest. These social network sites may place cookies on your device and use these to target advertising to you on their own or other websites. 

When you use romanoriginals.co.uk, you may notice some cookies that aren't directly from Roman. 

For example, pages that contain content from websites like YouTube or Facebook may send cookies from these websites when you view that content. We don't control the setting of these cookies, so we suggest you check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them. 

Details on Roman Third Party Cookies: 

Company Details | Classification | Purpose  
---|---|---  
Google | Performance | Google cookies allow us to use Google Analytics to measure web performance and advertising  
Double Click | Targeting | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our adverts and marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you  
Crealytics | Performance | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our adverts and marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you  
Rackspace | Functionality | Allows us to deliver the correct content to the page  
Scarab Research / Emarsys | Performance | Allows us to monitor and send emails, as well as personalise website content to help us make Roman more relevant to you.  
Fospha | Performance | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our adverts and marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you.  
Global-E | Functionality | Allows us to translate website for international markets and accept local payment methods.  
Bing | Performance | Bing cookies allow us to use Bing Analytics to measure web performance and advertising.  
Bing Ads | Targeting | Bing Ads cookies allow us to use the Bing Network to serve personalised advertising to you.  
AdRoll | Targeting | AdRoll cookies allow us to serve personalised advertising to you.  
Facebook | Targeting | Facebook cookies allow us to serve personalised advertising to you through the Facebook Network.  
Facebook | Performance | Facebook cookies allow us to use Facebook Analytics to measure web performance and advertising.  
Taboola | Performance | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our adverts and marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you  
AWIN | Performance | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our affiliate marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you  
Outbrain | Performance | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our adverts and marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you  
Ad Nexus | Performance | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our adverts and marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you.  
Pubmatic | Performance | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our adverts and marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you.  
Rubicon | Performance | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our adverts and marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you.  
Casale Media | Performance | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our adverts and marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you.  
Optimizely | Performance | These cookies allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our adverts and marketing on websites, to help us make Roman more relevant to you.  
TurnTo | Functionality | To allow our customers to leave product reviews to help Roman listen to customers and improve accordingly.  
HotJar | Performance | HotJar cookies allow us to use HotJar Analytics to measure web performance and monitor website behaviour.  
NCC | Performance | NCC cookies allow us to use NCC Analytics to measure web performance and monitor website behaviour.  
Sentry.io | Performance | Sentry.io cookies allow us to use Sentry.io Analytics to measure web performance and monitor website behaviour.  
New Relic | Performance | New Relic cookies allow us to use New Relic Analytics to measure web performance and monitor website behaviour.  
Feedbackify | Functionality | To allow our customers to leave website reviews and feedback to help Roman listen to customers and improve website improvements accordingly  
  
If cookies are not enabled on your computer, tablet or mobile then you will not be able to shop on romanoriginals.co.uk; you will be limited to browsing our products and the content on the site. 

There are a number of websites that can help you understand more about cookies and how to manage them. 

Websites that explain more details about cookies, how they work and how you can manage them include: 

  * www.allaboutcookies.org
  * www.aboutcookies.org
